John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Corporate Structure, RG 1 FA1793
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Board of Trustees, 1950-2019; 1; 33.99 Cubic Feet 87 letter document boxes and 5 half-letter boxes
  - Committees, 1950-2019; 3; 18.42 Cubic Feet 47 letter document boxes and 3 half-letter boxes
    - Investment Committee, 2001-2019; 8
      - Meeting, 2018 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        Materials for the Investment Committee Meeting on June 4, 2018. Includes minutes from March 2018; capital markets review; endowment performance; portfolio transparency; retirement plans review
      - Meeting, 2018 September 16 (Box 8, Folder 7)
        Materials for the Investment Committee on September 16, 2018. Minutes from the June 4, 2018 meeting; capital markets review; endowment performance and current positioning; woman- and minority-owned manager analysis; KF emerging markets portfolio.
      - Meeting, 2018 December 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
        Materials for the Investment Committee Meeting on December 3, 2018. Minutes from September 2018 minutes; capital markets review; endowment performance and current positioning; hedge fund allowable range; KF international equity portfolio. Observance and performance of Knight Foundation woman- and minority-owned firms
      - Meeting, 2019 March 11 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        Materials for the Investment Committee Meeting on March 11, 2019. Minutes of the December 2018 meeting; 2018 performance review; 2019 year-to-date capital markets review; endowment performance; private investment performance; Knight Enterprise Fund update; portfolio manager fees; comparative asset allocation and performance
      - Meeting, 2019 June 10 (Box 8, Folder 10)
        Materials for Investment Committee Meeting on June 10, 2019. John S. Knight Charitable Remainder Trusts, update; Investment Team Philosophy and approach; Investment Governance with Aon; Cambridge Associates, minutes from March 2019 meeting; portfolio overview; market update, performance attribution, women and minority manager summary, market outlook, manager additions and termination, retirement plan review
      - Meeting, 2019 September 8 (Box 8, Folder 11)
        Materials for the Investment Committee Meeting on September 9, 2019. Executive session; custody relationship; July 23 exec committee minutes; Full committee meeting minutes July 2019; Portfolio market review; performance reports
      - Meeting, 2019 December 2 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Mission Related Investment Sub-Committee, 2012-2017; 9
      - Minutes, 2012 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
        The sub-committee, consisting of chair Michael Maness, Juan Martinez, Ben Wirz and trustees Joi Ito, Chris Hughes and John Palfrey, have met several times beginning in the spring of 2012 to establish the framework for this new sub-committee which seeks to find for-profit ventures for KF to invest in. KF total budget for these type of investments is $10 million. The sub-committee approved a $100,000 investment in UMBEL, which helps publishers gain a clear picture of exactly who their digital audience is and what affinities, interets and behaviors they have. Exactly how an Enterprise Fund will work at KF is being worked out by the sub-committee. In addition to minutes of several meetings, other materials are: a memo from Ben Wirz re: Program Related Investment Profile for Daily Feats, an online network that helps people reach their personal goals; sub-committee structure and organization as of April 3, 2012; and charts outlining the Knight Enterprise Fund Portfolio, as of April 2012.
      - Meeting, 2012 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the March and April 2012 meetings, summaries of recommended PRI investments, summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, and June meeting minutes.
      - Meeting, 2012 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the June 2012 meeting, memo re: MRI Sub-committee Investment Policy, summaries of recommended PRI investments, summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, and September meeting minutes.
      - Meeting, 2012 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the September 2012 meeting, draft Knight Enterprise Fund One-Pager, summaries of recommended PRI investments, summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, and December meeting minutes.
      - Meeting, 2013 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the December 2012 meeting, summaries of recommended PRI investments, summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, and March meeting minutes.
      - Meeting, 2013 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Materials include an agenda, March 2013 minutes, summary of PRI investments and proposed investments, and summary of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments. Also included are June minutes.
      - Meeting, 2013 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the June meeting, summary of PRI investments, summary of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments and September meeting minutes.
      - Meeting, 2013 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the September meeting, summary of PRI investments, summary of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments. Also included are minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting, 2014 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Meeting, 2014 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the March meeting, summaries of recommended PRI investments, summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, and a Powerpoint presentation, "Knight Enterprise Fund".
      - Meeting, 2014 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the June meeting, summaries of recommended PRI investments, and summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments.
      - Meeting, 2014 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the September meeting, summaries of recommended PRI investments, and summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments. Sub-committee chair, Michael Maness, is leaving KF. He was replaced by John Bracken and Juan Martinez became committee chair.
      - Meeting, 2015 March (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Materials include an agenda, minutes of the December meeting, and summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies.
      - Meeting, 2015 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the March meeting; summary of PRI investments; and summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments; and update on KEF evaluation by Cambridge Associates.
      - Meeting, 2015 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the June meeting; memo re: new chair, Dennis Scholl, of the sub-committee [note: trustee Chris Austen replaced Scholl as chair at the December meeting]; summary of PRI investments; and summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments.
      - Minutes, 2015 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the September meeting; summary of PRI investments; and summaries of the Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies, new investments and proposed investments.
      - Meeting, 2016 February 29 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the December meeting; overview and update on the Knight Enterprise Fund; strategy deck review; industry outlook thoughts and feedback.
      - Meeting, 2016 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the February meeting; overview and update on the Knight Enterprise Fund; strategy deck review (updated); summaries of Knight Enterprise Fund portfolio companies and Knight program-related investment portfolio.
      - Meeting, 2016 September (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the June meeting; overview and update on the Knight Enterprise Fund (KEF); workshop PRI description; industry outlook, thoughts, feedback and summaries of KEF portfolio companies and summary of Knight PRI portfolio.
      - Meeting, 2016 December (Box 1, Folder 20)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the September meeting; overview and update on the Knight Enterprise Fund; industry outlook thoughts and feedback and summaries of KEF portfolio companies.
      - Meeting, 2017 February (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the December 2016 meeting; overview and update on the Knight Enterprise Fund (KEF); Memo of the Revised Valuation Standards; industry outlook thoughts and feedback and Industry outlook thoughts and feedback.
      - Meeting, 2017 June (Box 1, Folder 22)
        Materials include an agenda; minutes of the February 27, 2017 meeting; Future of the Knight Enterprise Fund (KEF); Summary of KEF portfolio companies and Summary of Knight PRI portfolio; Fund Activity in Q2 2017. This was the last meeting of MRI, it has been dissolved.
    - Nominating Committee, 1988-2019; 10
      The files contain meeting minutes and supporting documents regarding searches for new trustees and president.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1988-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        The nominating committee was concerned with the nomination of trustees and of the officers. The trustee search culminated in the nominations of Cesar Alvarez and Paul Grogran.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Minutes of Nominating Committee Meeting re: nomination of trustees and officers and the anticipated search for two new trustees in 2002..
      - Meeting Minutes, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Minutes of Nominating Committee Meeting re: renomination of trustees and officers and search for two new board members.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Meeting Minutes, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Minutes of Nominating Committee Meeting re: search for two new board members.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Minutes of Nominating Committee Meeting via teleconference re: recommendation of a chairman-elect as successor to Dr. Austen when he retires in March 2010.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2011 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Nominating Committee report and minutes of the meeting - all trustees up for reelection nominated. Mary Sue Coleman declined reelection to a second term. Officers: Chairman - Robert Briggs, Vice-Chair, Cesar Alvarez; plus two new officers: Vice President/Journalism and Media Innovation: Michael Maness and Vice President/Strategy and Assessment: Mayur Patel. The nominating committee recommends expanding the number of trustees temporarily in 2011 from 15 to 17 because 4 trustees will be going off the board in 2012. Also included are background materials sent to committee members in advance of the meeting, consisting of the nominating committee report to the Board; a chart listing trustee names, birth dates, year voted to board, trustee class and year retiring; and trustee area of expertise; meeting dates for 2011-2012 and trustee compensation.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2011 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Nominating Committee minutes re: personal interviews with four candidates for the board. The committee, based on the board resolution of 9/12/11 to allow the temporary increase in the number of trustees, recommends eight new trustees. Each new trustee is elected to different, short terms of one, two, or three years, after which he or she is eligible to be elected up to two, six -year terms. (March 2012: Borges, Considine, Kronick; March 2013: Hughes, Ito, Nelson; March 2014: Bell-Rose, Palfrey).
      - Nominating Committee Members, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        Correspondence from Lee Hills, chairman of the Nominating Committee, to Gerald Austen re: serving as an advisory member of the Nominating Committee during the illness of Jim Batten.
      - Nominating Committee Report to the Knight Foundation Trustees, 1994 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Nominating Committee's report to the Board of Trustees re: the filling of board vacancies left by Larry Jinks and Barbara Toomey with new trustees Jay Harris and Marjorie Knight Crane. Includes resumes for Harris and Crane.
      - Trustee Search, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        Correspondence among members of the Nominating Committee re: Board Vacancy left by Charles Clark.
      - Trustee Search, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Correspondence among members of the Nominating Committee re: replacing board of trustee members James Batten and C.C. Gibson with John Ong and Rolfe Neill.
      - Trustee Nominations, 1996 February 29 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        Memo from Creed Black to Lee Hills, Jerry Austen and Alvah Chapman re: opinions of the other board members as to who should assume the roles of chairman and vice-chairman of the Knight board following the retirement of Lee Hills.
      - Search Committee Chronology, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        Search Committee chronology of the search for new trustees and a new president, 1996-1997.
      - President/CEO Search, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        Memos from Trustees re: suggestions for qualities/background for the new President of the Knight Foundation prepared for the Search Committee meeting of August 1996. Memos were written by Gerald Austen, Lee Hills, Alvah Chapman, Marjorie Crane, Creed Black, Jill Conway, Henry Stanford and Rolfe Neill. Also included is a position description for the President's job; and a letter to Hodding Carter stating the terms of his employment as President.
      - Trustee Search, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        Memos re: candidates for the trustee position vacant with the resignation of Tom Johnson. John Rogers was ultimately elected.
      - Trustee Search, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Correspondence and background information re: potential trustees Gordon Gee and Henry Cisneros and biographical information on several others.
      - Trustee Search, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Minutes of a March 4, 2002 nominating committee meeting and a memo from Hodding Carter to the Nominating Committee with names and biographical sketches of potential trustees.
      - Report, 2005 March 14-15 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        List of Trustees to be re-elected and a list of officers for election.
      - President/CEO Search, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 31)
        Minutes of search committee meetings which culminated in the appointment of Alberto Ibarguen as President to succeed Hodding Carter. Gerald Austen chaired the search committee. Also included are memos from the search firm, SpencerStuart.
      - Report, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Report, 2009 March (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - By-law Issue, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        Emails between KF and Rod Petry, counsel, seeking clarification on terms of office for trustees nearing retirement and a possible change to the by-laws.
      - Report, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        Nominating Committee meeting minutes. Committee members continue to consider candidates for the Board.
      - Board of Trustee Correspondence, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 36)
        Memos re: Nominating Committee report to the Board of Trustees re: temporarily increasing the allowable number of trustees. Included are biographies of the proposed slate of new trustees; a chart showing trustee elections, appointments and retirements by year. The new trustees were elected to random 1, 2, and 3 year terms (to be followed by the possibility of 2 six year terms) to avoid having too many retirements in any given year. Also included are several emails re: trustee nomination talking points prepared by Alberto Ibarguen, and a question from a trustee (Olson) re: age minimum requirements.
      - New Trustee Orientation, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 37)
        Emails and draft memos re: new trustee orientation. Included is a tentative schedule for the December board meeting by Alberto Ibarguen, with input from Rob Briggs; trustee compensation planning; welcome email to new trustees from Alberto; a new trustees announcement plan by Marc Fest; administrative details; and three draft emails sent to all new trustees in advance of their first meeting in December.
      - Annual Meeting, 2013 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        Nominating Committee minutes of the annual meeting - all trustees up for reelection nominated. Terese Coudreaut is the Vice President/Human Resources and Administration and Secretary to the Board. Following the meeting, the committee reviewed and elected, via email, the nominee for Vice President, Communities and National Programs, Carol Coletta.
      - Meeting, 2013 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        Nominating Committee minutes of the meeting which concerned the process for electing a new chair-elect, who will be named at the September board meeting. Also included is a position description for the Chair, Board of Trustees.
      - Meeting, 2013 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        Memo, agenda, minutes and supporting materials re: nomination of a chair-elect. Includes responses by trustees to a straw vote on issues for the chair i.e.: term of office, election of a vice-chair and opinions about the suitability of candidates Bill Considine and John Palfrey. Also included are letters of nomination and resumes submitted by the candidates.
      - Meeting, 2013 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        Agenda, minutes and supporting materials for a teleconference meeting of the committee to discuss a replacement for retiring trustee, Marjorie Crane. Included are biographies of possible candidates. More candidates will be solicited at the December board meeting.
      - Meeting, 2014 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        Minutes and supporting materials for the annual meeting of the Committee, which was held in New York City. The committee proposed the reelection of all eligible trustees and officers and confirmed committee assignments for the year. The committee also met with two candidates for the Board. Both had a family connection to KF and investment experience. Included is biographical information on the two candidates, Christopher Toomey and Christopher Austen.
      - Meeting, 2014 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        Agenda and minutes of the January and March meetings. The committee approved the nomination of Christopher Austen for the Board.
      - Meeting, 2015 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        Agenda for the annual meeting of the Nominating Committee, memo outlining the assignments for re-election of trustees and officers, and committee assignments. Also includes minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting, 2015 November 30 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        Minutes of the meeting; schedule of upcoming Trustee retirements; biographies of more than 40 candidates nominated by trustees and senior staff; and a list of the Board's full skill set and diversity as well as its representation in Knight communities and areas of work. The Committee narrowed its focus to eight nominees to be reviewed by the full Board at its December meeting.
      - Meeting, 2016 February 29 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Materials sent to committee members include agenda; memo re: nominations for trustees, officers and committee chairs; and biographical sketches for 2016 trustee nominations.
      - Meeting, 2016 June 6 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        Materials sent to committee members include minutes of the February 29, 2016 committee meeting and biographical sketches on all nominated persons for trustees and the five finalists to fill three open positions on the board. Also included are minutes of the June 6 and June 30 meetings at which the committee interviewed two candidates and deferred the selection of a third. The nominees were to be confirmed by email vote.
      - Meeting, 2016 August 4-September 6 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Materials sent to committee members include certification of election of two new trustees. Christine Mayer was elected until March 2017, then will be eligible for two six year terms. Marty Baron was elected until March 2018, then will be eligible for two six year terms. Lynn Ross was appointed as vice-president of Communities and National Initiatives. Candidate bios for the third open seat were included.
      - Meeting, 2017 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        Minutes of Nominating Committee Meeting re: renomination of trustees, Board Chair, officers and search for two new board members for 2018.
      - Meeting, 2018 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        Minutes with Attachments A-C and materials for Nominating Committee meeting on March 5, 2018. Nominations for trustees, officers, board and committee chairs; 2018 committee assignments; trustee nomination discussions
      - Meeting, 2019 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        Minutes with Attachments A-C for Nominating Committee Meeting on February 12, 2019.
    - Pension Plan Administrative and Investment, 2002-2006; 11
      - Pension Plan Administrative and Investment, 2002 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Materials for the Pension Plan Committees Meeting of 3/11/2002, held in Miami, FL. Includes agenda, minutes of the March 2001 meeting, recent events, and summary reports on investment returns.
      - Pension Plan Investment Committee Meeting/Admin and HR Committee, 2003 March 10 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        Materials for the Pension Plan Committees Meeting of 3/10/2003, held in Miami, FL. Includes agenda, minutes of the March 2002 meeting, pension administration report, and retirement plan information.
      - Pension Plan Investment Committee Meeting/Admin. and HR Committee, 2004 March 8 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Materials for the Pension Plan Committees Meeting of 3/8/2004, held in Miami, FL. Includes agenda, minutes of the March 2003 meeting, pension administration report, cash balance plan status, retiree medical funding information, and retirement plan cost and funded status summary. Materials for the Administrative and Human Resources Committee include minutes of the December 2003 meeting, a staffing update with organization chart, medical and dental insurance information, and a summary analysis of 2003 general and administration expenses. Also included are minutes of the meeting.
      - Pension Plan Investment Committee Meeting/Admin. and HR Committee, 2005 March 14 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        Materials for the Pension Plan Committees Meeting of 3/14/2005, held in Miami, FL. Includes agenda, minutes of the March 2004 and March 2005 meetings, pension activity report, and retirement plan cost and funded status summary. Materials for the Administrative and Human Resources Committee include minutes of the December 2004 meeting, a staffing update with organization chart, medical and dental insurance information, commercial/business insurance and a summary analysis of 2004 general and administration expenses. Also included is the 1st Amendment to the Knight Foundation Section 403(b) Plan and Board Resolution adopting it.
      - Pension Plan Investment Committee Meeting/Admin. and HR Committee, 2006 March 13 (Box 4, Folder 6)